二零二四年广东省初中学业水平考试
英语试卷听力部分。
首先播放两分钟的音乐信号，
请监考老师调试好播音设备的音量。
system After After After After the After
音乐结束后，听力考。
考试正式开始。
嗯。
After music After the test begins After the After the
After the test begins
试听到此结束。
here a. After question
一，听说应用。
听句子，请根据所听内容选择符合提议的图画回答问题，
并在答题卡上将对应选项涂黑。
每个句子听两遍。
听每小题之前，你有五秒钟的时间阅读题目。
每小题听完后，你有五秒钟的答题时间。
1. Two days before Spring Festival, it was cold and snowy
2. Lily went back to her hometown in Guangdong by plane
3. Lily's village by the sea has become a very big town
4. Lily's parents live in house with two trees in yard
5. Lily's family had hot pot on the first day of Spring Festival
5. Lily's family 6.
Lily's had hot pot on the first day of Spring Festival 7.
听对话。
请根据每段对话的内容回答问题。
of conversation question After
从每小题。
我给的三个选项中选出一个最佳答案，
并在答题卡上将对应选项涂黑。
每段对话听两遍。
听每小题之前，你有五秒钟的时间阅读题目。
每小题听完后，你有五。
五秒钟的答题时间。
the Listen Listen Listen
听第一段对话，回答第六小题。
听第二段对话。
回答第七小题。
听第三段对话，回答第八小题。
听第四段对话，回答第九小题。
Have you finished reading the poems,
What? But the homework is to write a poem
Have you finished reading the poems, Jenny?
听第五段对话，回答第十小题。
Listen Look out of the window Wow, the lights are green and blue Let's go out and
听第六段对话，回答。
第十一至十二小题。
take a better look Mom, the TV has stopped working It's because of the Northern
lights Oh, terrible But they are so beautiful Look out of the window
Wow, the lights are green and blue Let's go out and take a better look
听第七段对话，回答第十三至十五小题。
Listen to seventh to
latest technology It can do many things Do you think musicians will be out of work
because of AI?
I don't think so AI cannot be as creative as humans
Linda, come here and listen to the music It sounds good I love light music Guess
what? It was created by AI Amazing!
I never imagined AI can write such wonderful music AI is the latest technology It
can do many things Do you think musicians will be out of work because of AI?
I don't think so AI cannot be as creative as humans
It can do think I text
听短文，请根据所听内容，从每小题所给的三个选项中选出一个最佳答案
，并在答题卡上将对应选项涂黑。
text Mary is 65 years old Last year she moved to a new community She felt lonely
短文听两。
变。
听短文之前，你有二十五秒钟的时间阅读题目。
听完后，你有二十五秒钟的答题时间。
because she had no friends there Then she had an idea She decided to go to a college
for old people The college offered many courses such as singing, dancing and so on
Mary decided to take a painting course She always dreamed to be a when she was a But
painting wasn't easy for her She couldn't do it well So she practiced with her
classmates twice a week She was not the best painter, but the most hard -working
learner The teacher praised her for her hard work
One of her works even won her a prize at a college And her classmates admired her
for that Because of the course,
Mary has got many friends now
Mary is 65 years old Last year she moved to a new community
She felt lonely because she had no friends there Then she had an idea She decided to
go to a college for old people
The college offered many courses such as singing, dancing and so on Mary decided to
take a painting course
She always dreamed to be a when she was a child But painting wasn't easy for her She
couldn't do it well So she practiced with her classmates twice a week
She was not the best painter, but the most hard -working learner
The teacher praised her for her hard work One of her works even won her a prize at a
college And her classmates admired her for that Because of the course, Mary has got
many friends now D.
听填信息。
You card Good morning everyone
你将听到一则校园大扫除活动的通知。
请根据所听内容填写下面的信息卡，
并将答案写在。答题卡对应题目的答题位置上。
短文听两遍。
听短文之前，你有二十五秒钟的时间阅读题目。
听完后，你有二十五秒钟的答题时间。
Our school is going to hold a cleanup activity at 4.30 p.m.
next Monday This is one of our labor education programs You need to bring large and
strong bags and other necessary tools The cleanup area will be divided into many
parts You should clean the area your head teacher has chosen for you Pay special
attention to the windows and the corners Mind your safety while you are doing that
Your head teacher will help you and check the final work This activity will make our
school cleaner It is also a chance to develop your practical skills and team spirit
Please form a and give the name list to your head teacher Thank you
Good morning everyone Our school is going to hold a activity at 4.30 p.m.
next Monday This is one of our labor education programs
You need to bring large and strong bags and other necessary tools
The cleanup area will be divided into many parts You should clean the area your head
teacher has chosen for you
Pay special attention to the windows and the corners
Mind your safety while you are doing that Your head teacher will help you and check
the final work This activity will make our school cleaner It is also a chance to
develop your practical skills and team spirit
Please form a and give the name list to your head teacher Thank you
听力理解部分到此结束。